The Huntington Library
Arthur M. Ellis Collection of Photographic Negatives
- Subject List
  - Churches
    - Central Los Angeles. Municipal buildings; Commercial buildings; Churches, ca. 1915; undated (Box 4, Item 396-428)
    - Los Angeles churches, 1870; 1895,; 1915,; 1920s,; undated (Box 7, Item 852-873)
    - Los Angeles. Plaza; Pico House; Plaza Church, 1857; 1891,; undated (Box 11, Item 1266-1291)
    - Los Angeles. Main Street between 1st and 3rd. Workmans store; Meyers residence; St. Vibianas Cathedral and views from St. Vibianas, 1870-1889; undated (Box 14, Item 1366-1379)
    - Los Angeles. Views from Pound Cake Hill; Red Sandstone Courthouse; St. Athenasius Church, 1891; 1895,; undated (Box 17, Item 1466-1475)
    - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along Fort Street/Broadway to about 5th including Fort St. Methodist Church, old City Hall, Potomac Block, 1871; 1883-1890,; 1902-1913,; undated (Box 17, Item 1476-1506)
    - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along S. Broadway from about 5th Street including Presbyterian Church, Synagogue and St. Vincent's School, 1870; 1880,; 1918,; undated (Box 18, Item 1507-1517)
    - Los Angeles. Central Park and vicinity, 1881; 1885,; undated (Box 19, Item 1556-1562)
  - Commercial Buildings
    - Central Los Angeles. Municipal buildings; Commercial buildings; Churches, ca. 1915; undated (Box 4, Item 396-428)
    - Central Los Angeles buildings, 1889-1925; undated (Box 8, Item 954-977)
    - Businesses and street scenes along, Los Angeles, 1st, Temple and Commercial Streets, Central Los Angeles, 1862-1872; undated (Box 12, Item 1309-1315a)
    - Los Angeles. North Main Street; Baker Block; Foy Brothers' Store; Lafayette Hotel; Baker Iron Works, 1868-1885; undated (Box 12, Item 1321-1340)
    - Temple Block and vicinity, 1862; undated (Box 13, Item 1341-1345)
    - Temple Block, 1876; undated (Box 13, Item 1346-1351)
    - Los Angeles. Main Street between 1st and 3rd. Workmans store; Meyers residence; St. Vibianas Cathedral and views from St. Vibianas, 1870-1889; undated (Box 14, Item 1366-1379)
    - Los Angeles. Main Street between 3rd and 6th including street views and buildings; Pacific Electric Building, 1883; 1900,; 1918,; undated (Box 14, Item 1380-1386)
    - Los Angeles. Pacific Electric Building (continued); Residences on Main St. (exact locations unknown), undated (Box 14, Item 1387-1390)
    - Los Angeles. Street scenes and buildings along Spring Street to 3rd Street including the Nadeau Block and Phillips Block, views of the Wolfskill Ranch from Spring Street and 3rd Street, 1889; 1892,; 1912,; undated (Box 15, Item 1396-1412)
    - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along Fort Street/Broadway to about 5th including Fort St. Methodist Church, old City Hall, Potomac Block, 1871; 1883-1890,; 1902-1913,; undated (Box 17, Item 1476-1506)
  - Documents, book passages, clippings
    - Spadra (continued), includes "Monkey Town" newspaper clipping, 1885; 1919,; undated (Box 23, Item 1700-1702)
    - Assessment, title page through page 4, 1850 (Box 27, Item 1862-1864)
    - Assessment, page 6 on, 1850; [Almost entire book was photographed but some pages are missing.] (Box 28, Item 1865-1873)
    - Los Angeles County. Court and legal documents and letters, 1850-1854; 1880,; 1908,; undated (Box 28, Item 1878-1897)
    - San Diego buildings and street scenes; Views of San Diego Harbor; Drawings from Phoenixiana; Other miscellaneous, 1874; undated; [Includes photographs taken by J.C. Parker.] (Box 30, Item 1952-1977)
    - Freemasonry. Lodges; Artifacts; Book passages; Miscellaneous, 1851; 1856,; 1908,; undated (Box 42, Item 2359-2370)
    - Miscellaneous. Book passages; Clippings; Printing, undated (Box 43, Item 2386-2395)
  - Gold Rush and Emigration
    - Gold Rush and emigration, Sutter's Fort and various mining camps; Emigrant trail; Miscellaneous, 1852; 1875,; 1918,; undated (Box 32, Item 2042-2059)
    - Stage Coaches, wagon teams, wagon trains, 1894; undated (Box 32, Item 2060-2071)
  - Godfrey, William M. photographs
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey 's numbers. Central Los Angeles, 1860; undated (Box 46, Item 2459-2482)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. Rubottom property, Spadra, 1874; undated (Box 46, Item 2483-2486)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. Central Los Angeles; L.J. Rose residence in San Gabriel, 1872; 1874,; undated (Box 46, Item 2487-2495)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. San Luis Rey and San Juan Capistrano Missions, undated (Box 47, Item 2496-2499)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. San Gabriel Valley, undated (Box 47, Item 2500-2512)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. Miscellaneous Los Angeles and Los Angeles County, 1874; undated (Box 47, Item 2513-2520)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs. Unnumbered miscellaneous Central Los Angeles and San Pedro, 1860; undated (Box 47, Item 2521-2529)
  - Historic sites
    - Schools; Campo de Cahuenga; Cahuenga Valley, 1877; 1896-1899,; undated; [Includes narratives by Otto Weid.] (Box 7, Item 893-908)
    - Monuments; Historic landmarks, undated (Box 9, Item 1152-1179)
    - Campo De Cahuenga, undated (Box 19, Item 1585)
    - Whittier and vicinity including Los Nietos; Pico Ranchita; Rio Hondo Battlefields and San Gabriel River, 1869; 1920-1921,; undated (Box 23, Item 1703-1711)
    - Sketches of battlefields; 1850 and 1852 California county divisions, undated; [Renderings.] (Box 28, Item 1874-1877)
    - Gold Rush and emigration, Sutter's Fort and various mining camps; Emigrant trail; Miscellaneous, 1852; 1875,; 1918,; undated (Box 32, Item 2042-2059)
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits, includes George Washington and Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2326-2336a)
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits including Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2337-2339)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 40, Items 2340-2345p)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 41, Items 2345q-2345ee)
    - U.S. history. Abraham Lincoln portraits and sites; Kit Carson; White House, undated (Box 42, Item 2346-2358)
  - Homes, residential buildings and residential streets scenes
    - Central Los Angeles buildings, 1889-1925; undated (Box 8, Item 954-977)
    - Los Angeles. Avila Adobe/Stockton's Headquarters, undated (Box 11, Item 1292-1295)
    - Abel Stearns residence/"El Palacio", 1850; undated (Box 12, Item 1316-1320)
    - Los Angeles. North Main Street; Baker Block; Foy Brothers' Store; Lafayette Hotel; Baker Iron Works, 1868-1885; undated (Box 12, Item 1321-1340)
    - Los Angeles. Main Street between 1st and 3rd. Workmans store; Meyers residence; St. Vibianas Cathedral and views from St. Vibianas, 1870-1889; undated (Box 14, Item 1366-1379)
    - Los Angeles. Pacific Electric Building (continued); Residences on Main St. (exact locations unknown), undated (Box 14, Item 1387-1390)
    - Los Angeles. Street scenes; Homes and buildings along S. Spring Street, 1875; 1889,; undated (Box 16, Item 1427-1430)
    - Los Angeles. Homes and buildings along San Pedro Street including the Lugo adobe, 1921; undated (Box 16, Item 1431-1436)
    - Los Angeles. Palm Drive; Agricultural Park; Shrine Auditorium; Chester Place, 1895; undated (Box 16, Item 1437-1440)
    - Los Angeles. Street scenes and homes on Bunker Hill and West Temple Street, including Exposition Hall, 1881; 1883,; undated (Box 16, Item 1441-1447)
    - Los Angeles. Bird's-eye views from Fort Hill. Buildings and street scenes along Hill Street, 1870; 1875,; 1910,; undated (Box 18, Item 1518-1538)
    - Los Angeles. Child's property, 1913; undated (Box 19, Item 1563-1565)
    - West Central Los Angeles. Various scenes including streets; buildings; Westlake Park and the Francisco farm, 1881-1890; undated (Box 19, Item 1566-1579)
    - Los Angeles. Farms and homes on future site of the Southern Branch of the University of California, undated (Box 19, Item 1580-1584)
    - Campo De Cahuenga, undated (Box 19, Item 1585)
    - North East and South East Central Los Angeles including Aliso Street; the Sainsevains property; Beaudry Reservoir; Boyle Heights, 1875; undated (Box 20, Item 1586-1600)
    - Pasadena, San Marino and Sierra Madre including the Lake Vineyard, Sunnyslope, El Molino Viejo and various street scenes, orchards and vineyards, 1871; 1885,; 1921,; undated (Box 21, Item 1622-1652)
    - Various San Gabriel Valley scenes, including Santa Anita Ranch, 1872; undated (Box 21, Item 1653-1662)
    - Rowland Property, 1921; undated (Box 21, Item 1663-1665)
    - El Monte region, including Savannah and Ellis Family Property, 1908-1920; undated (Box 22, Item 1666-1678)
    - Spadra (continued), includes "Monkey Town" newspaper clipping, 1885; 1919,; undated (Box 23, Item 1700-1702)
    - Whittier and vicinity including Los Nietos; Pico Ranchita; Rio Hondo Battlefields and San Gabriel River, 1869; 1920-1921,; undated (Box 23, Item 1703-1711)
    - Wilmington, including views of the town; Wilmington Exchange; Wilmington Barracks; Banning House, 1873; 1885,; 1918,; 1923,; undated (Box 23, Item 1718-1726)
    - Long Beach homes and buildings including Cerritos Ranch, 1885; undated (Box 24, Item 1744-1748)
    - Los Angeles County. Non-locational objects and unidentified locations; including "Rubbottom's bowie;" "Editorial Corps of the Weekly Comet;" Possible residences of Cameron Thom; Mayes family residence; First Ebell Club, undated (Box 24, Item 1761-1783)
    - Los Angeles County unidentified and miscellaneous includes street views, unidentified buildings and homes, engravings, 1878; undated (Box 26, Item 1784-1797)
    - Miscellaneous and unidentified Los Angeles, undated (Box 25, Items 1783a-1783o)
    - Orange County. Santa Ana street scenes, buildings, and residences, 1873; 1898,; undated (Box 28, Item 1898-1906)
    - Orange County. Santa Ana scenes and residences, including Santa Ana Depot, Opera House, undated (Box 29, Item 1907-1911)
    - City of Monterey, buildings and homes, 1850; undated (Box 30, Item 1985-1990)
    - San Francisco and Petaluma drawings and photos, includes Baldwin Hotel, M.G. Vallejo Adobe, 1849; 1865,; undated (Box 31, Item 2004-2011)
    - Miscellaneous. Unidentified buildings, houses, landscapes, undated (Box 44, Item 2414-2458)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. Rubottom property, Spadra, 1874; undated (Box 46, Item 2483-2486)
  - Hotels
    - San Fernando; San Gabriel; Eagle Rock; Pasadena; Los Angeles hotels, 1884-1919; undated (Box 7, Item 933-953)
    - Los Angeles. Plaza; Pico House; Plaza Church, 1857; 1891,; undated (Box 11, Item 1266-1291)
    - Los Angeles. North Main Street, Baker Block, Foy Brothers' Store, Lafayette Hotel, Baker Iron Works, 1868-1885; undated (Box 12, Item 1321-1340)
    - Los Angeles. Bella Union/St. Charles Hotel, photos and litho, 1858-1880; undated (Box 14, Item 1361-1365)
    - Arroyo Seco, Pasadena and Glendale including views of the Raymond Hotel and the Ostrich Farm, 1872; undated (Box 20, Item 1614-1621a)
    - El Monte region, including Savannah and Ellis Family Property, 1908-1920; undated (Box 22, Item 1666-1678a)
    - Spadra homes and ranches, including the Rubottom home and hotel, undated (Box 22, Item 1695-1699)
    - Santa Monica including Santa Monica Beach and Canyon; street scenes; Santa Monica Hotel; engravings, 1872; 1878,; undated (Box 23, Item 1727-1741)
    - Orange County. Santa Ana, street scenes, buildings, and residences, 1873; 1898,; undated (Box 28, Item 1898-1906)
    - Santa Barbara and Santa Barbara County, undated (Box 30, Item 1981-1984)
    - San Francisco and Petaluma drawings and photos, includes Baldwin Hotel, M.G. Vallejo Adobe, 1849; 1865,; undated (Box 31, Item 2004-2011)
  - Illustrations, drawings and sketches
    - Drawings of Los Angeles, 1850s (Box 11, Item 1264-1265a)
    - Los Angeles. Plaza; Pico House; Plaza Church, 1857; 1891,; undated (Box 11, Item 1266-1291)
    - Businesses and street scenes along, Los Angeles, 1st, Temple and Commercial Streets, Central Los Angeles, 1862-1872; undated (Box 12, Item 1309-1315a)
    - Los Angeles. Old Court House photos and engravings, 1868; 1875,; undated (Box 13, Item 1352-1360)
    - Los Angeles. Bella Union/St. Charles Hotel, photos and litho, 1858-1880; undated (Box 14, Item 1361-1365)
    - Santa Monica including Santa Monica Beach and Canyon; street scenes; Santa Monica Hotel; engravings, 1872; 1878,; undated (Box 23, Item 1727-1741)
    - Los Angeles County unidentified and miscellaneous includes street views, unidentified buildings and homes, engravings, 1878; undated (Box 26, Item 1784-1797)
    - San Diego buildings and street scenes; Views of San Diego Harbor; Drawings from Phoenixiana; Other miscellaneous, 1874; undated; [Includes photographs taken by J.C. Parker.] (Box 30, Item 1952-1977)
    - San Francisco and Petaluma drawings and photos, includes Baldwin Hotel, M.G. Vallejo Adobe, 1849; 1865,; undated (Box 31, Item 2004-2011)
    - Vischer illustrations arranged according to Ellis's numbering, 1860s-1870s; 1891,; undated (Box 33, Item 2084-2109)
    - Vischer illustrations. Locations from Orange County to Paso Robles, 1860s; undated (Box 33, Item 2110-2120)
    - Vischer illustrations. Paso Robles vicinity, 1864; undated (Box 34, Item 212-2123)
    - Vischer illustrations. Mountain trails and stage coach, 1860s; 1870s,; undated (Box 34, Item 2124-2131)
    - Miscellaneous illustrations, 1870 (Box 34, Item 2132-2132a)
    - Pen sketches of early prominent Jewish citizens of Los Angeles, undated (Box 39, Item 2300-2304)
    - Miscellaneous. Book passages; Clippings; Printing, undated; [No. 2395c removed for conservation.] (Box 43, Item 2386-2395g)
  - Industry
    - Firestone Tire Rubber; oil fields, 1907; 1919-1928 (Box 7, Item 827-851)
    - Los Angeles. North Main Street; Baker Block; Foy Brothers' Store; Lafayette Hotel; Baker Iron Works, 1868-1885; undated (Box 12, Item 1321-1340)
  - Land surveys, maps
    - Hansen surveys of various Los Angeles sites and Wilmington, 1864-1866; undated (Box 26, Item 1798-1825)
    - Hansen surveys, maps and notes; Various Los Angeles and San Gabriel properties, including Spadra and San Gabriel, 1853; 1855,; undated (Box 27, Item 1826-1837)
    - Ord's Survey, 1849 (Box 27, Item 1838-1841a)
    - Lecouvreur's Grade drawings, 1873 (Box 27, Item 1842-1848)
    - Waldemar surveys, 1857 (Box 27, Item 1849-1850)
    - Miscellaneous maps, of Los Angeles and San Diego Bay, makers unknown, undated (Box 27, Item 1851-1853)
    - Field notes on various Los Angeles area properties, unknown creator, 1855 (Box 27, Item 1854-1861)
    - Sketches of battlefields; 1850 and 1852 California county divisions, undated; [Renderings.] (Box 28, Item 1874-1877)
  - Missions
    - Missions. San Gabriel Arcangel; San Juan Capistrano, undated (Box 1, Item 60-82)
    - Missions. San Fernando Rey; San Buenaventura; Santa Barbara; Santa Ynez; La Purisima Concepcion; Santa Clara, undated; [Nos. 101, 108 missing as of December 2005.] (Box 1, Item 83-108)
    - Missions; Adobes, 1890-1931; undated (Box 6, Item 800-826)
    - San Diego Mission and surrounding grounds, 1874; undated; [Includes photographs taken by J.C. Parker.] (Box 31, Item 2012-2023)
    - San Gabriel Mission, undated (Box 31, Item 2024-2027)
    - Missions. San Buenaventura; Soledad; San Juan, 1874; undated (Box 31, Item 2028-2032)
    - Mission photos from Vischer and McPherson, organized by Ellis's numbering, undated (Box 31, Item 2033-2036)
    - Mission photos from Vischer and McPherson (continued), organized by Ellis's numbering, undated (Box 32, Item 2037-2041)
    - Vischer illustrations arranged according to Ellis's numbering, 1860s-1870s; 1891,; undated (Box 33, Item 2084-2109)
    - Vischer illustrations. Locations from Orange County to Paso Robles, 1860s; undated (Box 33, Item 2110-2120)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. San Luis Rey and San Juan Capistrano Missions, undated (Box 47, Item 2496-2499)
    - W.M. Godfrey photographs organized by Godfrey's numbers. Miscellaneous Los Angeles and Los Angeles County, 1874; undated (Box 47, Item 2513-2520)
  - Municipal buildings
    - Central Los Angeles. Municipal buildings; Commercial buildings; Churches, ca. 1915; undated (Box 4, Item 396-428)
    - Central Los Angeles buildings, 1889-1925; undated (Box 8, Item 954-977)
    - Los Angeles. Old Court House photos and engravings, 1868; 1875,; undated (Box 13, Item 1352-1360)
    - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along Fort Street/Broadway to about 5th including Fort St. Methodist Church, old City Hall, Potomac Block, 1871; 1883-1890,; 1902-1913,; undated (Box 17, Item 1476-1506)
    - Santa Cruz County. Benicia and Big Basin, 1857; 1918, undated; undated (Box 30, Item 1992-1997)
  - Parks
    - Los Angeles County parks, 1880-1894; 1920s,; undated (Box 7, Item 874-892)
    - Los Angeles. Palm Drive; Agricultural Park; Shrine Auditorium; Chester Place, 1895; undated (Box 16, Item 1437-1440)
    - Los Angeles. Central Park and vicinity, 1881; 1885,; undated (Box 19, Item 1556-1562)
    - West Central Los Angeles. Various scenes including streets; buildings; Westlake Park and the Francisco farm, 1881-1890; undated (Box 19, Item 1566-1579)
  - People
    - Portraits, 1849-1900; undated (Box 9, Item 1124-1151)
    - Native Americans, undated (Box 10, Item 1180-1189)
    - Portraits and people by name. Alexander through Dorsey, undated (Box 34, Item 2133-2164)
    - Portraits and people by name. Dreher through Lugo, 1864; 1890,; 1922-1923,; undated (Box 35, Item 2165-2210)
    - Portraits and people by name. Lugo through Stockton, 1855; 1921,; undated (Box 36, Item 2211-2254)
    - Portraits and people by name. Stowall through Yount, 1860; undated (Box 37, Item 2255-2277)
    - Portraits and people. Unidentified women, undated (Box 37, Item 2278-2282c)
    - Portraits and people. Unidentified men, undated (Box 37, Item 2283-2293)
    - Portraits and people. Unidentified men; Group photos, undated (Box 38, Items 2293a-2299d)
    - Pen sketches of early prominent Jewish citizens of Los Angeles, undated (Box 39, Item 2300-2304)
    - Native Americans. Portraits and group photos, undated (Box 39, Item 2305-2314)
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits, includes George Washington and Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2326-2336a)
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits, including Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2337-2339)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 40, Items 2340-2345p)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 41, Items 2345q-2345ee)
    - U.S. history. Abraham Lincoln portraits and sites; Kit Carson; White House, undated (Box 42, Item 2346-2358)
    - 5 x 7 glass negatives. Unidentified, undated (Box 47, Item 2530-2535)
  - Schools
    - Schools; Campo de Cahuenga; Cahuenga Valley, 1877; 1896-1899,; undated; [Includes narratives by Otto Weid.] (Box 7, Item 893-908)
    - Los Angeles. Street scenes and buildings along Spring Street to 3rd Street including the Nadeau Block and Phillips Block, views of the Wolfskill Ranch from Spring Street and 3rd Street, 1889; 1892,; 1912,; undated (Box 15, Item 1396-1412)
    - Los Angeles. Old High School on Pound Cake Hill and views from Pound Cake Hill, 1870-1885; undated (Box 16, Item 1448-1465)
    - Los Angeles. Buildings and street scenes along S. Broadway from about 5th Street including Presbyterian Church, Synagogue and St. Vincent's School, 1870; 1880,; 1918,; undated (Box 18, Item 1507-1517)
    - Various San Gabriel Valley scenes, including Santa Anita Ranch, 1872; undated (Box 21, Item 1653-1662)
    - El Monte region, including Savannah and Ellis Family Property, 1908-1920; undated (Box 22, Item 1666-1678)
  - Transportation
    - Stage Coaches, wagon teams, wagon trains, 1894; undated (Box 32, Item 2060-2071)
    - Central Pacific Railroad trains and routes, undated (Box 32, Item 2072-2076)
    - Southern Pacific Railroad locomotives, Newhall tunnel, undated (Box 33, Item 2077-2079a)
    - Miscellaneous transportation. Boats; Autos; Bicycle, 1900; undated (Box 33, Item 2080-2083)
    - Vischer illustrations. Mountain trails and stage coach, 1860s; 1870s,; undated (Box 34, Item 2124-2131)
  - U.S. History
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits, includes George Washington and Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2326-2336a)
    - U.S. history. Sites; Artifacts; Portraits, including Benjamin Foster, undated (Box 39, Item 2337-2339)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 40, Items 2340-2345p)
    - U.S. history. Benjamin Franklin, undated (Box 41, Items 2345q-2345ee)
    - U.S. history. Abraham Lincoln portraits and sites; Kit Carson; White House, undated (Box 42, Item 2346-2358)